LABEEB ABDULLAH SALIH

Technical Consultant Finastra Financial Services

PERSONAL INFORMATION

• **Birth Date**: 02 July 1981

Gender: MaleNationality: Iraq

• Residence Country: Iraq - Baghdad

Marital Status: SingleMobile: +964-790-221-5004

• Email: labeeb.abdullah@gmail.com

CAREER SUMMARY

B.Sc. in Computer Engineering with 13+ years related experience in the **IT & Telecom fields.**

Experience includes one year in financial services, three years in IT Management, one year in Project Management, two years in IT support, five years in Telecom and one year in IT & Telecom training.

Achievement appreciation letter from Zain Iraq HR for project management & successful acceptance test of Intelligent Network & Voucher Database swap project in 2009 resulting in network unification of Iraqna Co. and Atheer Co. Networks.

Achievement appreciation email from Zain Iraq IT director & Nokia Technical director for IT provisioning system swap & upgrade implementation with successful acceptance test in 2011 which reduce time, effort & cost for new services creation.

Achievement appreciation email from Zain Iraq IT director & Ericsson IT director for Activation system upgrades with implementation and successful acceptance test in 2012 which enable the company to manage fraud actions, auto-commissioning payment for dealers and raise company revenue dramatically.

Achievement appreciation letter from Zain Iraq HR for planning & implementation of IT systems swap & upgrade for the 3G mobile network (UMTS) in 2014 that lead to the launch of the 3.9G network in Iraq and increase company revenue.

KEY SKILLS

- Technologies: Intelligent Network, SMSC, Voice Mail, Business Support Systems, Provisioning & Activation, Mobile Banking, Dynamic Subscribers allocation.
- Red Hat Enterprise Linux System Administrator:
 RHEL 5.3, RHEL 6.3, RHEL 7.5, Red Hat Cluster Suite.

- Shell Scripting (bash & ksh): Sun Solaris, Digital UNIX &. HP UNIX.
- Database knowledge, Oracle 10.2 & 11.2g, MYSQL 5.5, IBM DB2 10.5 & Informix.
- Mobile networks: GSM (2G) & UMTS (3G).
 Mobile Network vendors: Alcatel-Lucent, Nokia Siemens, Ericsson AB & Huawei
- Wireless Networks: CDMA2000 (Huawei).
- Hardware platforms: HP, IBM & Sun Microsystems.
- Protocols: sftp, SS7, TCP/IP, CAP, INAP, SMPP, OSS/J, SOAP/HTTP(s), SSH, NFS, CIFS, LDAP & iSCSI.
- WebSphere Application Server Clusters –IBM (Version: 6.0.0.17, 6.0.0.34 & 8.5.5.2).
- JAVE SE 8 Fundamentals.

TRAINING

Academy Training

- Nokia Siemens: Provisioning system (SAAM 5.0 EP2) Operation & Maintenance in 2011, Beirut-Lebanon.
- Oracle 11g SQL Fundamentals I & II in 2011 at IT Training House, Baghdad-Iraq.
- Oracle 11g DBA I in 2012 at IT Training House, Baghdad-Irag.
- Linux Red Hat Essentials for RHEL5 in 2013 at IT Training House, Baghdad-Iraq.

On Job Training

- Asiacell Telecom: GSM Network & Services (2G) in 2005 at Asiacell Headquarters in Sulaymaniyah-Iraq.
- Nokia Siemens: Provisioning system (NPM 4.0) & Activation System (AS 1.0) in 2010 at Nokia Siemens office, Beirut-Lebanon.
- Nokia Siemens: Provisioning system (SAAM 5.0 EP2) service creation environment in 2011 at Nokia Siemens office, Beirut-Lebanon.
- Finastra financial services: Internet Banking & Mobile Banking configuration and installation in 2017 at Finastra office in Dubai, UAE.

Employment History

Technical Consultant Finastra Financial Services. Baghdad, Iraq.

(March 2017 – Present)

Responsibilities:

- Mobile Banking system Implementation.
- System Integration test support: Installation, validation, troubleshooting, log analysis.
- User Acceptance test support:
 UAT installation, weekly server, and mobile app deployment.
 Troubleshooting, test result verification, log analysis.
- Installation training for customer Engineers.
- Support the go-live preparation, go-live support, post live support, handover to operation.
- IBM AIX administration.
- IBM DB2 support.
- JAVA SE application support.

Senior IT Instructor IT Training House Co. Baghdad, Iraq

(March 2016 - Feb 2017)

Responsibilities:

- IT Instructor for the below courses:
 - -Red Hat System Administration I (RH124-RHEL7).
 - -Red Hat System Administration II (RH134-RHEL7).
 - -Red Hat System Administration III (RH254-RHEL7).
 - -Red Hat Linux Essentials (RH033-RHEL5).
 - -Mobile and Wireless Networks Fundamentals (2G GSM, 3G UMTS, 4G LTE & CDMA2000).

Provisioning & Activation Manager Ericsson (Zain Iraq Account) Baghdad, Iraq

(May 2012 – March 2015)

Responsibilities:

- Management for IT provisioning & Activation team members, tracking resource output in terms of different metrics, variables.
- Tracking and follow up knowledge transfer of team members, make sure of availability of redundant resource for each technology.
- Planning and implementation a plan for team enabling & training.
- Operation & Maintenance of Nokia SIM cards Activation System (AS), Serve At once Activation Manager (SAAM 5.0), Nokia Dynamic MSISDN allocation (DMA).
- Resolving and follow up customer tickets (Technical Query, Minor, Major & Critical).
- Emergency supports for the customer (24/7 support).

- Modifying, Creation and tracking of workflows via Nokia SAAM Service creation environment.
- System Integration testing (SIT) & User Acceptance testing (UAT) for new hardware & software within the planning and implementation phases.
- Perform backup & restore of OS & Database.
- Configure scheduled backups.
- Configure OS and DB alarms.
- Manage Application software licenses.
- Manage OS, DB & Application logs.
- Generation of scripts for OS health check, daily reports, and daily logs backup.
- Support for customer training.

Consultant and System Integration Technical Support Engineer Nokia Siemens Networks Baghdad, Irag.

(May 2010 – May 2012)

Responsibilities:

- Operation & Maintenance of Nokia SIM cards Activation System (AS), Serve At once Activation Manager (SAAM 5.0.
- Resolving and follow up customer tickets (Technical Query, Minor, Major & Critical).
- Emergency supports for the customer (24/7 support).
- Modifying, Creation and tracking of workflows via Nokia SAAM Service creation environment.
- System Integration testing (SIT) & User Acceptance testing (UAT) for new hardware & software during the planning and implementation phases.
- Perform backup & restore of OS & Database.
- Configure scheduled backups for DB, Configure OS and DB alarms.
- Manage Application software licenses, Manage OS, DB & Application logs.
- Generation of scripts for OS health check, daily reports, and daily logs backup.
- Support of customer training.

Intelligent Network & Value Added service Engineer Itisaluna Wireless Operator Co. Baghdad, Iraq.

(Jan 2010 – May 2010)

Responsibilities:

- Operation & Maintenance for Intelligent Network UNIX OS & Informix DB.
- Operation & Maintenance of SMSC UNIX OS & its Oracle DB.
- Marketing, Sales & Customer Care support.
- Call Data Records (CDR), logs & license management.
- Monitoring and clearing alarms for Huawei IN & SMSC.
- Sending Bulk SMS to subscribers.

- Support IN expansion, user acceptance test for new hardware elements SDP, SCP & USAU.
- Generation of scripts for daily reports.

Intelligent Network Engineer Shabakkat Cellular Co. Baghdad, Iraq.

(Apr 2009 – Jan 2010)

- Responsibilities:
- Nokia Siemens Intelligent Network (C@O) Operation & Maintenance.
- Project Management support for IN Swap from Alcatel (OSP2.3) to Nokia IN (C@O).
- Project management support & data dumps generation for voucher database swap.
- Daily System health check.
- Monitoring and clearing Alarms.
- Solving Customer Care problems.
- Generation of Daily and Monthly Reports.
- Support for user acceptance test for Nokia Siemens Intelligent Network & Voucher Database.
- Support for the project of currency change from USD to Iraqi Dinar (IQD).

Intelligent Network & Value added service Engineer Zain Iraq Telecom Co. Baghdad, Iraq.

(Dec 2006 – Apr 2009)

Responsibilities:

- Alcatel Intelligent Network (OSP 2.3), SMSC & Voice Mail Operation & Maintenance.
- Project Management support for IN Swap from Alcatel (OSP2.3) to Nokia IN (C@O).
- Project management support & data dumps generation for voucher database swap.
- Daily System health check.
- Monitoring and clearing Alarms.
- Solving Customer Care problems.
- Generation of Daily and Monthly Reports.
- Support for user acceptance test for Nokia Siemens Intelligent Network & Voucher Database.

Help Desk Agent Asiacell Telecom Co. Baghdad, Iraq.

(March 2005 – Dec 2006)

Responsibilities:

Customer Care support.

- Subscriber services support (Add/Remove GPRS, Voice Mail, Barring, Unbarring & Blacklist).
- · Generation of daily and monthly statistical reports.

Electrical Engineer Civilian Technologies Ltd. Baghdad, Iraq.

(Apr 2004 – Mar 2005)

Responsibilities:

- Power sites management & coordination.
- Planning and implementation for operation team.
- Support & generation of daily reports to the Iraqi Ministry of Electricity.
- Provide training for operation team.

Education

(September 1999 – June 2003)

Bachelor's degree, Computer Engineering. College of Engineering, Al-Nahrain University Baghdad, Iraq.

Languages

Arabic: Native

English: Fluent Speaker

References

References are available upon request.